marcelcutts

full-stack engineer

contact

Address withheld on public CV

Number withheld on public CV

me@marcelcutts.com marcelcutts.com

languages

English fluency German basic

programming

Python, JavaScript C#, Java, C++ SQL, PLSQL CSS3 & HTML5

methodologies

TDD, BDD Scrum/Kanban UX, UCD

synopsis

Full stack developer blended with client facing consultancy experience.

From stacking together a PC from salvaged parts to popular web applications, over the years I have absorbed technologies and systems making me a capable generalist. My thirst for learning endures, and I will continue to take knowledge hostage into the future.

When not sat behind a computer for work or for fun, I mostly climb rocks, fight heavy people, trek across the arctic and play guitar talentlessly.

education

2007–2012 **Physics** with industrial experience

Thesis on the superstate of b-meson oscillations.

employment

2011-201 **Tessella**

Analyst Developer

During my time at Tessella I have had opportunities to work on an exceptional variety of development and consultancy projects across domains. This has ranged from designing and implementing large scale n-tier applications to analysing and advising on processes in the consumer industry.

Internally, I have championed new technologies and methodologies, as well as led small teams and mentoring developers.

2010 **Deutsches Elektronen-Synchrotron**

Hamburg, Germany

University of Bristol

Oxford, United Kingdom

Particle Physicist

My efforts at the DESY institute focused on combining knowledge of physics and programming ability to contribute to an upcoming particle accelerator, the International Linear Collider. As part of my role, I regularly gave presentations to international audiences to promote scientific updates from the department and attended numerous specialised lectures.

2009-2010 **De La Rue**

London, United Kingdom

Research and Development Scientist

De La Rue allowed me contribute to upcoming security products across many areas of science. Throughout I developed my own ideas, mostly within the realm of software, but also within materials science and optics.

Within the broader team, I participated in designing, prototyping and refining oncoming products, including work in holographics, polymer development, photonic crystals and printed electronics.

2004-2010 Various part time or short term employment

Worldwide

Various service positions

Number of roles during younger years ranging from park keeper to bar tender.

selection of relevant experience

This section would normally contain a selection of experience relevant to a particular position, but as this edition will be public available on the web, I have included a varied assortment of projects below instead.

Data sandbox - visualisation and analytical engines

JavaScript, Python, D3, HTML5/CSS3, Bottle, Jasmine, SqlLite, UX

An academic institute is currently running a national birth cohort study investigating 100,000 people over a number of years. My role as an analyst and developer was to provide quantitative feedback which outlined the possible impact of study steering decisions.

Once I had begun to understand the domain and the needs of the various stakeholders, I created and refined software that allowed the institute to visually play with their data and parameters in real-time, receiving instant feedback on their potential decisions through detailed predictive metrics.

I created this system through a strong JavaScript front-end utilising D3 and other libraries, and python for numerical work on the back-end. This was achieved using a number of agile methodologies which I later expanded the use of within the study as a whole to help the institute adapt more rapidly to changing requirements.

Consequently, this gave the institute the power to not only quickly, but confidently make decisions in a time constrained field. As an additional bonus, due to the design efforts, it found a secondary purpose as presentation tool for displaying figures and scenarios externally.

Pharmaceutical portal

C#, Python, MSSQL, Entity Framework, MVC4, nUnit, nSubstitute, WF, WCF, Unity, CI The portal offers a number of services providing speciality pharmaceuticals, including a Global Access Program which is intended to provide unlicensed or trial-phase drugs to patients in need, internationally and domestically.

A solution was required to handle requesting, validation, procurement, shipping and tracking of these drugs by health care professionals, via pharmaceutical suppliers, while fulfilling all necessary industry regulations. As the software gained clients, analytics and reporting were developed to aid in overseeing the complex pharmaceutical chain.

A web-based application was created, by myself in a small scrum team, to satisfy these requirements. We used an MVVM architecture built on .Net's MVC4 framework as the foundation and applied principles of agile, with rigorous unit testing and continuous integration testing throughout.

The result is a highly accessible portal for users and clients, which automated several previously manual processes. This allowed the client to rapidly expand its program range with minimal additional effort.

Image analysis suite

Python, PIL, hardware hacking

During my time at the department, a significant shift was going through the security printing industry which focused less on chemistry in inks and watermarks and looked more towards advanced optical effects as deterrents to counterfeiting. Due to the traditional nature of the company, no programming and few quantitative data systems or processes existed. I proposed and spear-headed an image analysis suite that could output several metrics on the goodness of produced products, as well as checking for the viability of various new technologies. Technologically, this was achieved through a combination of python programming and hardware hacking with available supplies. This created a brand new automated quality assurance process, which allowed products relying on tighter tolerances to be manufactured, and gave the research division previously unavailable insights.